Guide to the George D. Woods Papers
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
George D. Woods Papers,
1935-1982
Woods, George D. 1901-1982.
ca. 565 items (5 v., 40 boxes and 26 oversize items).
Columbia University Rare Books and Manuscript Library, Butler Library, New York, NY l0027.
4078355
Biographical Note
Investment banker who served as president of the World Bank from 1963 to 1968. Prior to which he had been chairman of the board of the First Boston Corporation, of which he was also a founder.
Scope and Content
Correspondence, speeches, articles, economic data, photographs, scrapbooks, appointment books, telephone logs, memorabilia, and printed materials dealing almost exclusively with Woods' presidency of the World Bank. The papers consist largely of volumes of speeches and articles by Woods, world economic briefs and scrapbooks of clippings and photographs. The collection includes a number of signed and inscribed photographs including Mohammad Ayub Khan, Hassan II of Morocco, Ferdinand E. and Imelda Marcos, John F. Kennedy, Lyndon B. Johnson and Gamal Abdul Nasser. Also in the collection are books from Woods' library, some of them inscribed; printed materials by and about Woods; and silver and other memorabilia.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into 4 series:
Series I: Photographs
Series II: Audio Visual
Series III: Card Files
Series IV: Oversize Material
Subjects
World Bank.; International finance.; Banks and banking, International.; Photoprints; Scrapbooks; Bankers
Access Restrictions
The following boxes are located off-site: 4-95. You will need to request this material from the Rare Book and Manuscript Library at least twenty-four (24) hours in advance to use the collection in the Rare Book and Manuscript Library reading room.
Country Economic Briefs, April l968, may not be used without written permission of the World Bank.
Acquisition
1982 Papers Woods, Louise (Mrs. George D.) Gift
1983 Addition Woods, Louise (Mrs. George D.) Gift
1984 Addition Woods, Louise (Mrs. George D.) Gift
1985 Addition Woods, Louise (Mrs. George D.) Gift
05/12/86 correspondence files, calendars, and phone lists. Woods, Mrs. George Gift
Gift of Mrs. George D. Woods, l982, l983, l984, l985, l986.
- Series I: Photographs
  - Annual meetings of World Bank, [v.p.], 1963-1967, (1 album) (Box 276)
  - Visit to Yugoslavia, May 1967, (1 album) (Box 276)
  - Portraits (George D. Woods, Bachrach, Gittings, et al.) (Box 14-13-01)
  - World Bank Board of Governors, September 1964 (Box 14-13-01)
  - World Bank Executive Directors (2), January 1963 (Box 14-13-01)
  - World Bank Executive Directors (2), January 1965 (Box 14-13-02)
  - World Bank Board of Governors, September 1966 (Box 14-13-02)
- Series II: Audio Visual
  - Two (2) motion picture films, Japan & Egypt, 1957 & 1958 (Box 278)
- Series III: Card Files
  Names and addresses of people in different countries; often giving datails about their rank and position.
  - Abu Dhabi - Great Britain (P) (Box 95)
  - Great Britain (Q) - Jamaica (Box 96)
  - Japan - Sweden (Box 97)
  - Switzerland - Zambia (Box 98)
- Series IV: Oversize Material
  - Subseries IV.1: Scrapbooks
    - Scrapbooks - Philippines, (1 volume) (Box 275)
    - Scrapbooks #1 & #2, [v.p.], 1962-1968, (2 volumes) (Box 274)
    - Scrapbooks #3 & #4, [v.p.], 1962-1968, (2 volumes) (Box 277)
    - Scrapbook - Trip to Africa, 1966, (1 volume) (Box 276)
    - Scrapbook - Life of George D. Woods, (1 volume) (Box 279)
    - Scrapbook - Condolence letters re. death of George D. Woods, (1 volume) (Box 279)
  - Subseries IV.2: Documents
    - Appointment as Colonel, U.S. Army, 1947 (Box 14-13-02)
    - First Boston Corporation Resolution honoring George D. Woods, 1962 (Box 14-13-02)
    - World Bank Advertisement, 1965 (Box 14-13-02)
    - World Bank Appreciation, April 1968 (Box 14-13-02)
    - Order of Merit, Mauritania, 1969 (Box 14-13-02)
    - Order of Merit, Italy, 1971 (Box 14-13-02)
    - Bowdoin Honorary degree, 1964 (Box 14-13-02)
    - Notre Dame Honorary degree, 1964 (Box 14-13-02)
    - Harvard Honorary degree, 1965 (Box 14-13-02)
    - Columbia Ubiversity Honorary degree, 1966 (Box 14-13-03)
    - Kenyon College Honorary degree, 1968 (Box 14-13-03)
    - Academic hoods, (6 hoods) (Box 14-13-03)